A Guide to the Charles Olson Research Collection 1969.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series I: Works, undated, 1927-1969
  - C. Collected Poems
    - Right in my eye the west sun... Photocopy. 1p., ca. 1959. (Box 17, Folder 663)
    - Rocking meter over desolation. Typescript. 3p., January 20, 1968. (Box 17, Folder 664)
    - Rosy, It Was. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., February 10-11, 1958. (Box 17, Folder 665)
    - Rufus Woodpecker... Typescript. 7p., April 26, 1958. (Box 17, Folder 666)
    - Rufus Woodpecker. Thermofax copy. 3p. (Box 17, Folder 667)
    - Said Adam. Carbon copy. 2p., ca. May 1945. (Box 17, Folder 668)
    - Sans Name. Typescript. 1p., ca. September 1948. (Box 17, Folder 669)
    - The sea is an archeology... Manuscript. 1p., ca. May - August 1953. (Box 17, Folder 670)
    - A Second Musical Form, For Dave Young. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., October 5, 1960. (Box 17, Folder 671)
    - Sections from "Buffalo Ode." Manuscript. 3p., March 25, 1964. (Box 17, Folder 672)
    - The Seven Songs. Typescript. 1p., ca. June 1955 - May 1956. (Box 17, Folder 673)
    - Seventeenth century men who founded this land... Typescript. 1p., ca. February 20, 1962. (Box 17, Folder 674)
    - Shang dynasty oracle bone 2 say. Manuscript. 1p., ca. September 1962 - June 1963. (Box 17, Folder 675)
    - She. Typescript. 1p., February 16, 1945. (Box 17, Folder 676)
    - The She-Bear. Typescript/Carbon copy. 36p., March 25-27, 1950. (Box 17, Folder 677)
    - The She-Bear. Manuscript/Typescript. 8p., March 1950; ca. 1957-1962. (Box 17, Folder 678)
    - She, Thus. Typescript. 1p., March 3, 1945. (Box 17, Folder 679)
    - Shenandoah. Typescript. 1p., October 14, 1964. (Box 17, Folder 680)
    - Shut in kept off... Empty., December 1962. (Box 17, Folder 681)
    - Siena, 1948. Typescript. 2p. (Box 17, Folder 682)
    - Signs. Typescript/Photocopy. 2p., September 27, 1950. (Box 17, Folder 683)
    - Signs. Typescript/Photcopy. 2p., September 27, 1950. (Box 17, Folder 684)
    - Sin is inferiority... Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1961-1965. (Box 17, Folder 685)
    - Sing, Mister, Sing. Typescript. 1p., January 27, 1945. (Box 17, Folder 686)
    - Sit by the window and refuse my father... Typescript. 1p., December 2, 1958. (Box 17, Folder 687)
    - A Six Inch Chapter - in Verse. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., ca. February 27, 1958. (Box 17, Folder 688)
    - Small Birds, To Agree With the Leaves... Typescript. 4p., ca. May 1955. (Box 17, Folder 689)
    - The Snow. Typescript. 1p., December 17, 1961. (Box 17, Folder 690)
    - Snow White was always waiting for The Prince... Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 3p., January 23, 1963. (Box 17, Folder 691)
    - Some partial cloudiness will flow locally... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., September 12, 1962. (Box 17, Folder 692)
    - The Song. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., December 13, 1958. (Box 17, Folder 693)
    - A Spring Song for Cagli. Typescript. 1p., March 1947. (Box 17, Folder 694)
    - Stone and Flower Series. Manuscript/Typescript/Photcopy. 17p., ca. June 1958. (Box 17, Folder 695)
    - A Story. Typescript. 1p., ca. June 1954. (Box 17, Folder 696)
    - The Story of an Olson, and Bad Thing. Manuscript/Typescript. 18p., June 5-6, 1950. (Box 17, Folder 697)
    - The Story of an Olson, and Bad Thing. Carbon copy. 8p., June 1950. (Box 17, Folder 698)
    - The Soul. Typescript. 7p., ca. June 1954. (Box 17, Folder 699)
    - Sut Lovingood. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1955-1958. (Box 17, Folder 700)
    - Tanto e Amara. Typescript. 1p., ca. November 22, 1948. (Box 18, Folder 701)
    - Telegram. Typescript. 1p., February 1945. (Box 18, Folder 702)
    - The Tellers (Those Who Brought It In). Typescript. 1p., November 1949. (Box 18, Folder 703)
    - Tenementy twilightish landscape... Typescript. 1p., ca. 1958-1962. (Box 18, Folder 704)
    - A Tentative Translation of a Newly Discovered 'Homeric' Hymn. Typescript. 3p., August 20, 1955. (Box 18, Folder 705)
    - There is No River Which is Called Lethe. Manuscript/Typescript. 4p., October 11, 1961. (Box 18, Folder 706)
    - There they were... Typescript. 1p., December 30, 1962. (Box 18, Folder 707)
    - There Was a Youth Whose Name Was Thomas Granger. Typescript. 2p., 1946 or 1947. (Box 18, Folder 708)
    - These Days. Manuscript/Typescript. 4p., January 10, 1950. (Box 18, Folder 709)
    - The Thing Was Moving. Empty., May 11, 1952. (Box 18, Folder 710)
    - This man's weakness is straw... Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1959-1962. (Box 18, Folder 711)
    - This Year. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., ca. November 1965 - 1968. (Box 18, Folder 712)
    - Thoughts of the Time. Manuscript. 5p., September 1956. (Box 18, Folder 713)
    - To a Poet Who Read in Gloucester. Manuscript. 3p., October 4, 1962. (Box 18, Folder 714)
    - To the She-Bear (The 1st Song). Manuscript/Typescript. 9p., March 1950; ca. 1957-1962. (Box 18, Folder 715)
    - To Try to Get Down One Citizen... Typescript. 1p., ca. November 1958 - March 1963. (Box 18, Folder 716)
    - La Torre. Typescript. 1p., 1946. (Box 18, Folder 717)
    - La Torre. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., October 1946 - June 1950. (Box 18, Folder 718)
    - The Tower. Typescript. 5p., November 1946. (Box 18, Folder 719)
    - A Toss, for John Cage. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 10p., ca. July-August 1952. (Box 18, Folder 720)
    - The Town. Typescript/Carbon copy/Photocopy. 6p., ca. June 2, 1945. (Box 18, Folder 721)
    - A Translation. Carbon copy. 1p., ca. November 1945. (Box 18, Folder 722)
    - A Translation from Havelock Ellis. Typescript. 1p., ca. March 11, 1945. (Box 18, Folder 723)
    - The Treatment. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1958. (Box 18, Folder 724)
    - Trinacria. Typescript. 1p., ca. February 1946. (Box 18, Folder 725)
    - Troilus. Published copy. 1p., ca. July 1948. (Box 18, Folder 726)
    - True Numbers. Typescript. 2p., December 9, 1954. (Box 18, Folder 727)
    - Turn now and rise... Manuscript. 2p., April 14, 1966. (Box 18, Folder 728)
    - 2 Propositions and 3 Proof. Typescript/Carbon copy. 4p., ca. November 1945. (Box 18, Folder 729)
    - Undazzled, keen, love sits... Typescript. 1p., ca. April 5-6, 1958; November 16, 1958. (Box 18, Folder 730)
    - Under every green tree... Empty., ca. January 1950 - January 1951. (Box 18, Folder 731)
    - The unfinished (raw) hero... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., March 10, 1964. (Box 18, Folder 732)
    - Variations done for Gerald Van De Wiele. Typescript. 3p., ca. April 1956. (Box 18, Folder 733)
    - variations Done for Gerald Van De Wiele. Typescript. 12p., ca. April-May 1956. (Box 18, Folder 734)
    - The Vessel, Say, and Its Element. Typescript. 7p., March 1950. (Box 18, Folder 735)
    - War on the Mind in a Time of Love. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1952-1957. (Box 18, Folder 736)
    - Well. Typescript. 1p., April 1953. (Box 18, Folder 737)
    - When I think of what Fitz Lane didn't do... Typescript. 1p., August 30, 1968. (Box 18, Folder 738)
    - White Horse. Photocopy. 1p., 1940-1946. (Box 18, Folder 739)
    - The Whole World. Typescript/Photocopy. 10p., August 25, 1955. (Box 18, Folder 740)
    - The winds which blew my daughter... Typescript. 1p., August 7, 1952. (Box 18, Folder 741)
    - Winter. Typescript. 2p., December 8, 1945. (Box 18, Folder 742)
    - The Winter After. Typescript. 1p., ca. December 1945. (Box 18, Folder 743)
    - A Woman's Nipples Is the Rose of the World. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., October 5, 1960. (Box 18, Folder 744)
    - West. Typescript. 6p., ca. 1959-1964. (Box 18, Folder 745)
    - West. Manuscript/Typescript. 9p., ca. 1959-1964. (Box 18, Folder 746)
    - West. Setting typescript prepared for printer by Tom Raworth. 4p., ca. 1959-1964. (Box 18, Folder 747)
    - West 6. Manuscript. 1p., March 4, 1964. (Box 18, Folder 748)
    - What's Wrong With Pindar. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., ca. December 1957 - March 1958. (Box 18, Folder 749)
    - When one age goes... Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1961-1963. (Box 18, Folder 750)
    - What Had To Go. Typescript. 2p., December 12, 1961. (Box 18, Folder 751)
    - Who. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1957-1958. (Box 18, Folder 752)
    - Who slays the Spanish sun... Typescript. 1p., ca. December 1956. (Box 18, Folder 753)
    - Will: termite mothers... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., October 16, 1964. (Box 18, Folder 754)
    - Will: the rat... Typescript. 1p., October 17, 1964. (Box 18, Folder 755)
    - The Will To. Manuscript. 1p., May 3, 1960. (Box 18, Folder 756)
    - Winter Solstice. Typescript. 1p., December 8, 1958. (Box 18, Folder 757)
    - With what I got out... Typescript. 1p., ca. 1958-1959. (Box 18, Folder 758)
    - Without the Season of Structure... Typescript. 2p., ca. 1958-1959. (Box 18, Folder 759)
    - The Writ. Typescript/Photocopy. 8p., ca. February 3-11, 1957. (Box 18, Folder 760)
    - X to the Nth. Typescript. 1p., ca. November - December 1946. (Box 18, Folder 761)
    - X to Zebra. Typescript. 1p., ca. November - December 1946. (Box 18, Folder 762)
    - The Year is a Great Circle... Typescript. 5p., January 1958. (Box 18, Folder 763)
    - The Year is a Great Circle or The Year is a Great Mistake. Carbon copy. 1p., January 15, 1958. (Box 18, Folder 764)
    - The Yellow of the Mask. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 6p., October 31, 1960. (Box 18, Folder 765)
    - You know, verse is a lovely thing... Typescript. 1p., ca. January - May 1957. (Box 18, Folder 766)
    - Your Eyes. Typescript. 1p., December 1946. (Box 18, Folder 767)
    - The Collected Poems of. Typescript. 10p., January 2, 1953. (Box 19, Folder 768)
    - Common Place; The Eye; The Table. Typescript. 1p., January 2, 1953. (Box 19, Folder 769)
    - The Drum World. Manuscript/Photocopy. 3p. Written on "Sum No. 6, April 1965, San Francisco.", April 10, 1965. (Box 19, Folder 770)
    - The Encounter. Typescript. 2p., ca. August 8, 1956. (Box 19, Folder 771)
    - An "Enthusiasm". Manuscript. 2p. Written on booklet, "Provincial Museum of Natural History and Anthropology: Report for the Year 1962" and accompanying envelope., October 9, 1965. (Box 19, Folder 772)
    - The Lamp. Manuscript. 1p. Written on restaurant placemat., October 14, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 773)
    - So the Norse were neurotic... Manuscript. 1p., 1966. (Box 19, Folder 774)
  - D. Nation of Nothing But Poetry: Supplementary Poems
    - Adamo! Adamo! Manuscript/Typescript. 7p., ca. 1948-1949. (Box 20, Folder 775)
    - Add An Edda. Typescript. 6p., ca. 1957. (Box 20, Folder 776)
    - The Advantage. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 5p., January 10, 1950. (Box 20, Folder 777)
    - All covered with feathers... Manuscript/Typescript. 5p., ca. May 8, 1962. (Box 20, Folder 778)
    - And Now: The World! Folded TS signed, sent R. Souster, returned in his letter dated February 2, 1958. See also Dan Rice's letter dated ca. February 6, 1958. Manuscript/Typescript. 5p., ca. January 17, 1958. (Box 20, Folder 779)
    - Apoptic. "For Richard Bridgeman." Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., ca. April-May 1962. (Box 20, Folder 780)
    - As of what's ahead... Manuscript. 1p., September 17, 1951. (Box 20, Folder 781)
    - Atalanta ran swift course... Typescript. 2p., 1940. (Box 20, Folder 782)
    - Auctour. Addressed "Dear E.P." Manuscript/Typescript. 1p., ca. May 12, 1946. (Box 20, Folder 783)
    - Birth's Obituary. See also "Key West II" notebook. Manuscript/Typescript. 1p., March 9, 1945. (Box 20, Folder 784)
    - Black Mt. College Has a Few Words For A Visitor. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 5p., June 16, 1952. (Box 20, Folder 785)
    - Capricorn. Typescript. 1p., early 1940's. (Box 20, Folder 786)
    - Crown of Nails. Typescript. 1p., early 1940's. (Box 20, Folder 787)
    - The Clouds. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., ca. 1952-1954. (Box 20, Folder 788)
    - A Day, of a Year. Typescript. 1p., June 21, 1950. (Box 20, Folder 789)
    - De Bonox. Typescript. 1p., ca. May 29, 1950. (Box 20, Folder 790)
    - A direct downward path... Typescript. 1p., October 31, 1960. (Box 20, Folder 791)
    - Ego Scriptor. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1953-1954. (Box 20, Folder 792)
    - Eve, and Lilith and Adam and Pie. Manuscript. 2p., ca. May 1960. (Box 20, Folder 793)
    - The Feast. Typescript. 11p., May 29, 1954. (Box 20, Folder 794)
    - February, 1968. Manuscript/Typescript. 5p., February 28, 1968. (Box 20, Folder 795)
    - For A.K., Enniscorthy, Keene, Virginia. Typescript. 2p., January 4, 1946. (Box 20, Folder 796)
    - For joe. Typescript. 1p., April 3, 1950. (Box 20, Folder 797)
    - For PV himself alone and god bless him. Typescript. 6p., ca. August-September 1953. (Box 20, Folder 798)
    - For the Children, in the Novel, Mr. Hellman. Typescript/Photocopy. 2p., ca. October 1954. (Box 20, Folder 799)
    - 1492-1942. Typescript. 1p., March 15 1945. (Box 20, Folder 800)
    - The Friend. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1952-1957. (Box 20, Folder 801)
    - From Troilus (A Mask). Typescript. 3p., June-July 1948. (Box 20, Folder 802)
    - Future/open... Typescript. 1p., ca. 1958-1959. (Box 20, Folder 803)
    - Glyphs. Typescript. 1p., ca. July 16-21, 1951. (Box 20, Folder 804)
    - The grain of December. Typescript. 1p., December 1962. (Box 20, Folder 805)
    - A Greeting To A Lord High Canadian Lawyer's Wife. Manuscript. 1p., ca. May 1960. (Box 20, Folder 806)
    - How One Feels About It... Manuscript/Typescript. 1p., ca. 1957-1959. (Box 20, Folder 807)
    - Idle Idyll. Typescript. 4p., ca. July 9, 1952. (Box 20, Folder 808)
    - In the automotive store. Manuscript. 21p., October 30, 1962. (Box 20, Folder 809)
    - In Black. Manuscript/Typescript. 7p., May 8, 1962. (Box 20, Folder 810)
    - Jim Bridger first white man into Yellowstone... Typescript. 1p., June 1964. (Box 20, Folder 811)
    - Kar-ch-ro-donta. Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1962 - Spring 1963. (Box 20, Folder 812)
    - Ladies and Gentlemen, the Center Ring! Carbon copy. 1p., ca. July 4, 1946. (Box 20, Folder 813)
    - Lady Mimosa... Typescript. 6p., March 27, 1950. (Box 20, Folder 814)
    - Lalage. Carbon copy. 2p., ca. September 1946. (Box 20, Folder 815)
    - Lustrum. Typescript/carbon copy. 2p., ca. April 1945. (Box 20, Folder 816)
    - Mavrodaphne. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., 1940. (Box 20, Folder 817)
    - Melville's sense of blooming late... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., January 22, 1966. (Box 20, Folder 818)
    - Mindanao. Typescript. 1p., early 1940s. (Box 20, Folder 819)
    - The Moon. Typescript. 1p., ca. November 1946. (Box 20, Folder 820)
    - My Father. Typescript. 1p., March 4, 1945. (Box 20, Folder 821)
    - The nation is nothing but poetry. Manuscript. 1p., November 17, 1962. (Box 20, Folder 822)
    - No. Typescript. 1p., early 1940s. (Box 20, Folder 823)
    - Northman, What of Yourself? Typescript. 3p., ca. May 1948 - March 1949. (Box 20, Folder 824)
    - A Notice, For All American Mechanics. Typescript. 1p., August 11, 1952. (Box 20, Folder 825)
    - Of Love. Typescript. 1p., June 22, 1946. (Box 20, Folder 826)
    - The Old Physics Restored... Typescript. 2p., ca. June 1955 - May 1956. (Box 20, Folder 827)
    - O'Ryan - #11. Manuscript/Typescript. 9p., November 1955. (Box 20, Folder 828)
    - The Osiris Boat. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., December 15, 1961. (Box 20, Folder 829)
    - The Picture. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1953-1957. (Box 20, Folder 830)
    - Planted the fruit skin and all... Typescript. 2p., November 29, 1963. (Box 20, Folder 831)
    - Raphael. Typescript. 1p., early 1940s. (Box 20, Folder 832)
    - The Retort. Typescript/Photocopy. 8p., 1954. (Box 20, Folder 833)
    - A rivulet of soil... Empty., ca. May 1960. (Box 20, Folder 834)
    - Sea Song. Typescript. 1p., early 1940s. (Box 20, Folder 835)
    - A Shadow, Two. Typescript. 2p., May 29, 1950. (Box 20, Folder 836)
    - She, Thus. Manuscript/Typescript. 1p., ca. March 3 - August 25, 1945. (Box 20, Folder 837)
    - So Gentle. Typescript. 1p., June 22, 1950. (Box 20, Folder 838)
    - Stravinsky. Typescript. 2p., 1948 - June 13, 1949. (Box 20, Folder 839)
    - There are sounds... Typescript. 4p., ca. August 24 - November 1950. (Box 20, Folder 840)
    - There is a goddess of earth... Manuscript. 11p., ca. March 1963. (Box 20, Folder 841)
    - These people and their Amusement Park... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., November 20, 1965. (Box 20, Folder 842)
    - This is Thoth speaking. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1955. (Box 20, Folder 843)
    - Trivittata. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., November 30, 1961. (Box 20, Folder 844)
    - Vinal. Typescript/Photocopy. 2p., April 1952. (Box 20, Folder 845)
    - The Way of the Word. Typescript. 1p., ca. September 1946. (Box 20, Folder 846)
    - Where They Came From. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., December 12, 1961. (Box 20, Folder 847)
    - Who it is who sits... Typescript. 4p., ca. December 1949. (Box 20, Folder 848)
    - Who Sings Against Things. Typescript. 1p., early 1940s. (Box 20, Folder 849)
    - the wild geranium... Manuscript/Typescript. 1p., ca. Spring 1963. (Box 20, Folder 850)
    - Willie Francis and the Electric Chair. Typescript/Carbon copy/Newsprint. 12p., ca. May 1947. (Box 20, Folder 851)
    - You need never fear... Photocopy. 1p., ca. May 16, 1964. (Box 20, Folder 852)
    - Your Witness. Typescript. 2p., ca. January 1948 - November 1950. (Box 20, Folder 853)
  - E. Unpublished poems
    - 1941-1952 (Box 21)
    - Chemistry. Typescript. 3p., ca. 1941. (Box 21, Folder 854)
    - Ur; The Kiss. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1941. (Box 21, Folder 855)
    - Cain's Child. Carbon copy. 1p., ca. February 1941. (Box 21, Folder 856)
    - What Day. Typescript. 1p., May 1941. (Box 21, Folder 857)
    - Notes: September 21, 1942. Typescript. 1p. (Box 21, Folder 858)
    - To Harvey Brett, About His Story "A Pair of Legs". Typescript. 1p., ca. 1945. (Box 21, Folder 859)
    - Day's War with Night. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1945. (Box 21, Folder 860)
    - Gethsemane. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1945. (Box 21, Folder 861)
    - First Act, or I, Ishmael. Manuscript/Typescript. 6p., ca. 1945. (Box 21, Folder 862)
    - American. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., January 26, 1945. (Box 21, Folder 863)
    - Valentine. Carbon copy. 1p., February 16, 1945. (Box 21, Folder 864)
    - Of arms and of men... Typescript. 2p., February 19, 1945. (Box 21, Folder 865)
    - The True Life of Arthur Rimbaud. Typescript. 9p., February 20-24, 1945. (Box 21, Folder 866)
    - Three Translations. Manuscript/Typescript. 4p., ca. March 11, 1945. (Box 21, Folder 867)
    - Where. Manuscript. 1p., March 28, 1945. (Box 21, Folder 868)
    - Where. Typescript. 1p., March 28, 1945. (Box 21, Folder 869)
    - Consider. Typescript. 1p., May 12, 1945. (Box 21, Folder 870)
    - The Narrative of Cabeza de Vaca. Manuscript/Typescript. 4p., ca. 1945. (Box 21, Folder 871)
    - To K. -- II. Typescript. 2p., ca. January 1946. (Box 21, Folder 872)
    - La Constanza. Manuscript. 1p., ca. May 1946. (Box 21, Folder 873)
    - A Child's Address. Typescript. 1p., ca. June - September 1946. (Box 21, Folder 874)
    - Broch Our Hawk. Typescript. 2p., ca. July 19, 1946. (Box 21, Folder 875)
    - Canton. Typescript. 1p., ca. November 1946. (Box 21, Folder 876)
    - The Word As Discovery. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1947-1948. (Box 21, Folder 877)
    - So. Typescript. 1p., February 1947. (Box 21, Folder 878)
    - Ring, Sing. Typescript. 1p., Fall 1945. (Box 21, Folder 879)
    - The earth is for the living... Typescript. 1p., 1946. (Box 21, Folder 880)
    - Unlike a Room. Typescript. 3p., February 8, 1947. (Box 21, Folder 881)
    - Queen of Martyrs save us... Typescript. 1p., ca. June 9, 1947. (Box 21, Folder 882)
    - Offer. Typescript. 1p., ca. January 1948 - November 1950. (Box 21, Folder 883)
    - The Epilogue. Typescript/Photocopy. 4p., ca. 1948. (Box 21, Folder 884)
    - The Prologue to The Rime of Cabeza de Vaca. Typescript. 2p., ca. January 9, 1948. (Box 21, Folder 885)
    - Gahndi dead. Gangster rule complete. Manuscript. 2p., ca. 1948. (Box 21, Folder 886)
    - El Granada, January, 1948. Manuscript. 1p. (Box 21, Folder 887)
    - February 14, 1948. Typescript. 1p. (Box 21, Folder 888)
    - These States. Typescript. 1p., ca. June 8, 1948. (Box 21, Folder 889)
    - A Tao for H.G. Typescript. 1p., June 1948. (Box 21, Folder 890)
    - A Tao for R.R. Typescript. 1p., June 1948. (Box 21, Folder 891)
    - A Tao for R.K. Typescript. 1p., June 1948. (Box 21, Folder 892)
    - For R.K. Typescript. 1p., June 1948. (Box 21, Folder 893)
    - Taos. Photocopy. 3p., June 1948. (Box 21, Folder 894)
    - The Tao. Typescript. 1p., June 1948. (Box 21, Folder 895)
    - In Answer to a Request for Dirge Words... Typescript. 1p., ca. April 1, 1949. (Box 21, Folder 896)
    - The Sumer Fable. Typescript. 2p., May - October 1949. (Box 21, Folder 897)
    - The Huluppu Tree [The Sumer Fable]. Typescript. 2p., May - October 1949. (Box 21, Folder 898)
    - Ilias. Typescript. 1p., May 11, 1949. (Box 21, Folder 899)
    - Lover I: In my breat bones I am shy... Typescript. 1p., December 1949. (Box 21, Folder 900)
    - The Mundane Wheels and Arcane Shoes. Photocopy. 1p., ca. late 1940's. (Box 21, Folder 901)
    - The contradiction isn't me... Manuscript. 1p., ca. late 1940's. (Box 21, Folder 902)
    - And end to analysis. An end! Manuscript. 1p., ca. late 1940's. (Box 21, Folder 903)
    - What it is to look into a human eye... Typescript. 1p., 1949-1950. (Box 21, Folder 904)
    - A robin, berries and leaves... Typescript. 1p. Fragment., ca. 1950's. (Box 21, Folder 905)
    - Rhubarb flowering... Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1950's. (Box 21, Folder 906)
    - Genesis. Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1950's. (Box 21, Folder 907)
    - Let's you and me be Chinese... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., ca. 1950. (Box 21, Folder 908)
    - My fate as exorciser... Typescript. 2p., ca. 1950. (Box 21, Folder 909)
    - Again, Spring. Typescript. 1p. Fragment., 1950. (Box 21, Folder 910)
    - Again, Spring. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1950. (Box 21, Folder 911)
    - Uh-Huh. Typescript. 1p. (Box 21, Folder 912)
    - Christ, sd D, Christ... Typescript. 1p., ca. January 19, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 913)
    - 'Cento. Typescript. 3p., January 19, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 914)
    - Cento. Typescript. 2p., ca. January 19, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 915)
    - 'Cento. Typescript. 1p., January 19, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 916)
    - God Sports and Plays. Typescript. 1p., January 20, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 917)
    - God Sports and Plays. Typescript. 4p., January 20, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 918)
    - f' you. Typescript. 2p., February 22, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 919)
    - Inst Session No. 11. Typescript. 4p., March 22, 1953. (Box 21, Folder 920)
    - Creeley, N.H. Typescript/Photocopy. 2p., 1950. (Box 21, Folder 921)
    - A Visitation. Typescript. 6p., March 13, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 922)
    - This be thisbe, pyramus... Typescript. 1p. Fragment., March 31, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 923)
    - A Song from a Masque to be called Delight. Typescript. 1p., May 30, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 924)
    - The necessity to be other than a citizen... Typescript. 1p., June 8, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 925)
    - The hell is, in this business... Typescript. 1p., ca. June 16, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 926)
    - Gli Amanti. Typescript. 3p., ca. June 22, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 927)
    - Gli Amanti. Manuscript. 1p., ca. June 22, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 928)
    - Gli Amanti. Carbon copy. 1p., ca. June 22, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 929)
    - Gli Amanti. Typescript. 1p., ca. June 22, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 930)
    - A Round and a Canon. Typescript/Photocopy. 2p., ca. July 31, 1951. (Box 21, Folder 931)
    - In Answer to a Request for Dirge Words... Typescript/Carbon copy. 4p., ca. June 24, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 932)
    - Go boy who sleeps... Typescript. 1p., August 1950. (Box 21, Folder 933)
    - I cannot let my language go free... Typescript. 1p., November 7, 1950. (Box 21, Folder 934)
    - A Glyph From the 1st Century. Typescript/Photocopy. 3p., ca. 1951. (Box 21, Folder 935)